A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 9, Accession 9 FA1191
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Clippings and Reference, 1948-2011; 15; 5.23 Cubic Feet 14 containers
  - U.S. - China Relations - Historic Background, 1967-1975; Still Images: 2 black and white 5x7 glossy prints. (Box 33, Folder 308)
    Clippings and articles. Includes letter from Jay Robinson, 1973 October 24, enclosing group photos of the North China Union Language College, class of 1921-1922, and Harvard-Yenching University, Class of 1936.
  - U.S. - China Foreign Relations, 1969-1976 (Box 33, Folder 309-311)
  - U. S .- China - Trade, 1969-1972 (Box 33, Folder 312-313)
  - U.S .- China - Trade, 1973-1976 (Box 34, Folder 314)
  - Pre-1971 Articles on Prospects for Contacts with China (Box 34, Folder 315)
  - U.S. - China Relations - Bilateral Talks, 1971-1976 (Box 34, Folder 316)
  - Nixon Visit to China (February 1972), 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 317-321)
    Pre-trip statements, historical perspective, first leg of trip; Discussions; Sightseeing and Entertainment; U. S. Public Reaction; Chinese Reactions.
  - Shanghai Communique, 1972 February 28 (Box 34, Folder 322)
    File contains English text of the Sino - U. S. Joint Communique.
  - Henry A. Kissinger Visits to China, 1972-1975 (Box 34, Folder 323)
  - President Ford Visit to China, 1975 December (Box 34, Folder 324)
    Includes U. S. Reactions and Editorials on the trip, Chinese Coverage.
  - Nixon's Second Visit to China, 1976 February (Box 34, Folder 325)
  - Travelers to China - General, 1970-1977 (Box 35, Folder 326-327)
  - Travelers to China - Journalists, 1971-1977 (Box 35, Folder 328-330)
  - Travelers to China - Medical and Scientific, 1971-1975 (Box 35, Folder 331)
  - Travelers to China - Scholars, 1970-1976 (Box 35, Folder 332)
    Includes items labeled "Public Opinion - Scholars."
  - Travelers to China - U. S. Politicians, 1972-1976 (Box 35, Folder 333)
  - Travelers to China - James Schlesinger Visit, 1976 September-October (Box 35, Folder 334)
  - Travelers to China - Edgar Snow, 1967-1972 (Box 36, Folder 335)
  - Americans Living in China, 1970-1976 (Box 36, Folder 336)
  - American Table Tennis Visit to China, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 337)
  - Chinatowns (New York and San Francisco), 1978 (Box 36, Folder 338)
  - Articles in the American Press on China (Education, Economy, Culture), 1982-1984 (Box 36, Folder 339)
    Small selection of articles presumably intended for use as briefing material.
  - Beijing Spring - General, 1989-1994 (Box 49, Folder 470)
  - Beijing Spring - Explanations, 1989-1990 (Box 49, Folder 471)
  - Demonstrations, 1989 April - August; 1990 (Box 49, Folder 472)
  - Government Response to Unrest (1989 April 15 - June 3) (Box 49, Folder 473)
  - Government Response to Unrest, 1989 June (Box 49, Folder 474)
    File includes English-language publications by New Star Publishers presenting the government response to the uprising, and an Amnesty International report on the Massacre of June 1989 and Its Aftermath.
  - Tiananmen Square - Eyewitness Accounts, 1989; 1994 (Box 49, Folder 475)
  - Tiananmen Square - Government Crackdown, 1989 June 3-4 (Box 49, Folder 476)
  - Government Crackdown, 1989 June - 1991 (Box 49, Folder 477)
  - Tiananmen Square - Aftermath, 1989-1998 (Box 49, Folder 478)
  - Editorials on Tiananmen Square and China, 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 479)
  - U.S. - China Dialogue, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 480)
  - Zhu Rongji and Chinese Mayors Delegation - Press Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 50, Folder 481)
    Mayor of Shanghai Zhu Rongji headedup the visit of a delegation of Chinese mayors to the U. S. in July 1990.
  - Atmospherics of China in the early 1970s, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 482)
    China in New York, vol. 1, no. 1.
  - Civil Society and NGOs (Readings), 1996-2004 (Box 50, Folder 483-484)
    Includes material on conferences and lectures; Ford Foundation report on Non-Governmental Social Development Groups in China, 1996.
  - Civil Society and NGOs, 1996-2002; 2008-2011 (Box 50, Folder 485)
    Includes notes on meetings and conferences.
  - President Clinton's Visit to China (Clippings), 1998 June (Box 50, Folder 486)
  - Health In China, 1990-1991 (Box 50, Folder 487)
  - Khrushchev - Mao Conversations, 1958-1959 (Box 50, Folder 488)
  - Religion in China (Clipping), 1998 (Box 50, Folder 489)
  - China, Taiwan, and Hong Kong, 1976-1977; 1996; 2003 (Box 50, Folder 490)
  - Taiwan, 1999-2001 (Box 50, Folder 491)
  - Academic and Media Freedom in China, 2002 April (Box 61, Folder 596)
    Woodrow Wilson Center Asia Program Special Report. Seminar held October 24, 2001.
  - Campaign Finance Scandal, 1999-2000 (Box 61, Folder 597)
  - Separated Oversized Material (Box 65)
- Special Formats - General, 18
  Series 18, Special Formats - General, consists of various working files and other poorly identified materials, housed on floppy disks. The series is at present unprocessed; folder titles reflect content information such as we have it.
  Other digital materials in RG 9 are described within the appropriate subject series.
  See also FA1318, for available NCUSCR audiovisual material.
  - Clean, 1998 April 6; Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Maildocs; Oksenberg, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Ford Survey: Atlantic Council (attachments); Brookings; CISAE; CAN; GWU (attachments); Heritage; ICEE; Monterey, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Ford Survey: NCAFP; NCUSCR; PISA; STIMSON; APCSS; Atlantic Council; Bonnie Glaser; CEIP; CFR; Denver; Duke; Fairbank Center; Georgetown; ICSG; MCPA; NAL; Naval War College; NEAED; Nixon Center; Olin Institute; PAC Forum, CSIS; Rand, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Ford Survey: CSIS; GW Elliott School; NDU; Shambaugh Interview; Stanley? Foundation; USC; West Point?; WW Center, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Taxi; Allie, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Not Now Kid. BMP (use "Paint" to open), Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - National Committee on US-China Relations, Room Assignment List, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - 99 Safety Net, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Disk numbered "7", Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
    Crossed out on label: Annual Report, Fy1994; Board, Exec.; Budgets; Finance; Computer; COP; Dispatch, Dialogue Report; DML; Environ; Ernst; all 1995.
  - Ed 99 - Spring; Ed 99 - Fall, 1999; Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Taiwantuan, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Broadcasting Delegation (Docs include: Background on China TV Industry, BBI, Ministry and CCTV info, CEN excerpts, Irv Drasnin, Issues to be addressed for Broadcasting Del., Natl and Regional TV Networks; Notes from EDK, email from BJ re USIS and BC Del., Pan Hua, Types of TV Pgs aired in HK, Willie Brent), Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch.
    Access copy currently unavailable. Researchers interested in accessing digital media in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Please contact an archivist for information.
  - HC Members text file, 1585, Digital, 3.5 inch floppy disk
  - Illegible Title (Hogane? Itin, 1992 October 10; 1993 October), Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - Luce, Boorstin, Gergen, Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - Itineraries, Charts. COP 90; CP 92, TWP 92, CAN J 91, May 92; NGO 92, Z191, CIIS 93; ICIR 91; TEP, SOP 92; Mideast 91; EDK and SB, 91, Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - Brochures, Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - JB - Dialogue (notation on envelope). Label on disk crossed out: Back-up from PC - Jan B. ACIL, BIISS, CW, Env SPCH, USIA, 12-15-92., Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - SC (Clean) Crossed out on Label: Back-up from PC - Jan B. FAC, Govs, HG, HM, NOW, 12-15-92., Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk
  - Backup (illegible). JB Notes in Write Format, 1992 February 6; Digital 5.25 inch floppy disk